Rita Saltz collection
Rita Saltz collection
1955-1986
1955 1986
Coll003
Saltz Rita Seplowitz
1 box (.25 linear feet)
1 box
.25 linear feet
The collection contains announcements, newsletters, and manuscript drafts of Rita Saltz, as well as books, photographs, and comic books. Of particular interest is the correspondence from Jane Yolen [Stemple] the well known author of science fiction, fantasy, and childrens books. Also noteworthy is a signed and dated partial manuscript by science fiction writer Harlan Ellison of his screenplay based on Isaac Asimov's book I, Robot.
University of Maryland, Baltimore County Albin O. Kuhn Library and Gallery UMBC 1000 Hilltop Circle Baltimore, MD 21250 410-455-2353 speccoll@umbc.edu
Jane Yolen (1939 - ) is a science fiction and children's book author. Yolen has received both the Nebula Award from the Science Fiction/ Fantasy Writers of America and the Mythopoeic Fantasy Award. Harlan Ellison (1934 - ) is a science fiction author who has also worked in television, radio, and comics and graphic narratives. Ellison is also a recepient of the Nebula Award, in addition to the World Science Fiction Society's Hugo Award and the Silver Pen for Journalism by PEN International.
Arranged by accession.
No restrictions.
Folder list available.
These papers were acquired as three separate donations along with several books, some photographs and a large collection of comic books from Rita Seplowitz Saltz. Accessions from Saltz include: MSS 1995-09, 1996-13, 1996-14, 1997-05, 1998-01.
Yolen Jane; Ellison Harlan; Comic books, strips, etc.; Asimov Isaac 1920-1992; Saltz, Rita Seplowitz Archives; Yolen, Jane Correspondence; Science fiction, American 20th century Women authors
- Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  MSS 1996-13, MSS 1996-14
- Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Jane Yolan [Stemple], 1966, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Jane Yolan [Stemple], 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Jane Yolan [Stemple], 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, Jane Yolan [Stemple], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newsletters and Announcements, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  1 newsletter and 1 announcement regarding the constitution of the World Science Fiction Society. MSS 1996-13, MSS 1996-14
- Correspondence, 1955, 1966-1967, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  MSS 1997-05
- Manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  MSS 1997-05. Partial manuscript draft of screenplay, "I, Robot" Harlon Ellison
- Correspondence, Isaac Asimov, Aug 24, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  MSS 1998-01
- Correspondence, Jane Yolan [Stemple], 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)